Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/kozyrkov (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Statistics

Data Analysis

R

Languages

English

Russian

Afrikaans

Cassie Kozyrkov

CEO, Google's first Chief Decision Scientist, Al Adviser, Decision Strategist, Keynote Speaker (makecassietalk.com), LinkedIn Top Voice

New York, New York, United States

Summary

Cassie is Google's former Chief Decision Scientist and a soughtafter Al advisor, working with senior leaders at places like Lenovo, NASA, and Gucci. She is currently CEO of Data Scientific and is known for founding the field of Decision Intelligence.

Cassie is a beloved personality in the data and AI community, followed by over half a million tech professionals. She is also a renowned keynote speaker and writer. (If you'd like her to speak at your event, here's her booking form: makecassietalk.com)

In almost 10 years at Google, Cassie personally trained over 20,000 Googlers in data-driven decision-making and AI and has helped over 500 projects implement decision intelligence best practices. Before that, she served in Google's Office of the CTO as Chief Data Scientist. The rest of her 20 years of experience was split between data science, consulting, lecturing, and academia.

If you've had a good chuckle while learning about AI, statistics, or decision-making, chances are you've encountered her writing, which has reached millions of readers. She has been honored as a LinkedIn Top Voice for 5 years and as a #1 Artificial Intelligence writer on Medium for 7 years.

Experience

Data Scientific
Chief Executive Officer
September 2023 - Present (1 year 1 month)
New York, New York, United States

Speaking and advisory services. Request form: makecassietalk.com

Federal Reserve Bank of New York

Innovation Advisory Council Member March 2023 - Present (1 year 7 months)

New York, United States

Google

9 years

Chief Decision Scientist
March 2018 - September 2023 (5 years 7 months)

Greater New York City Area

Decision Intelligence is an interdisciplinary field concerned with all aspects of decision-making. It combines Data Science (statistics, machine learning, AI, analytics) with the Behavioral Sciences (psychology, neuroscience, economics, and the managerial sciences).

I serve as a thought leader in this new discipline, guiding Google and the world in making safe, effective use of Al and data.

Chief Data Scientist, Office of the CTO November 2017 - March 2018 (5 months)

Greater New York City Area

My mission is to democratize artificial intelligence and guide business leaders in harnessing the transformative power of machine learning.

Technical Director, Al and Data March 2017 - November 2017 (9 months) New York City Metropolitan Area

Youngest ever member of Google's Office of the CTO, specializing in Al and data science.

I'm also a coauthor of Google's Technical Director training program to teach others how to succeed in the role.

Statistician 2014 - April 2017 (3 years) Greater New York City Area

My roles are: statistician, machine learning expert, mentor, data scientist, evangelist, decision scientist, and consultant. I bridge the gap between leaders and quantitative analysts / researchers.

As Google's statistics and machine learning sensei:

* I've advised 200+ teams at Google on their analytics processes.

- * My ideas have sparked 400+ new projects.
- * I've trained 20,000+ analysts/leaders/engineers in rigorous data-driven decision-making and/or using machine learning to transform their work.

Largest projects in: Search Advertising, Google Maps, Machine Intelligence, Infrastructure, YouTube

Self-Employed
Data Science Consultant
January 2004 - May 2014 (10 years 5 months)

Data science consulting and analytics services for clients from government organizations, private sector firms, and academia.

North Carolina State University 2 years Statistics Instructor 2013 - 2014 (1 year) Raleigh-NC

Large statistics courses for all majors.

Mathematical Statistics PhD Student 2012 - 2014 (2 years) Raleigh, NC

Statistical Computing, Advanced Topics in Statistics: Big Data, Special Topics in Statistics: Data Mining, Applied Time Series Analysis, Applied Multivariate Data Analysis, Advanced Probability and Measure Theory, SAMSI Computational Advertising, Statistical Methods II, Statistical Consulting, Statistical Theory I, Statistical Theory II, Linear Models and Variance Components, Stochastic Processes, Doctoral Research, Supervised Doctoral Teaching, R Programming

Duke University
Neuroeconomics PhD Candidate
2010 - August 2012 (2 years)

Psychology & neuroscience with specialization in transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) methods and the science of decision-making.

Center for Cognitive and Social Neuroscience at the University of Chicago 2 years Project Manager 2008 - 2010 (2 years)

Coordinated lab research projects and team effort. Designed and ran experiments.

Research Assistant - Prof. John List 2008 - 2008 (less than a year)

Charitable contributions and decision-making research with Professors Steve Levitt and John List.

Education

University of Chicago BA, Economics

Duke University
PhD ABD, Psychology and Neuroscience

North Carolina State University
Master's degree, Mathematical Statistics

Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University BCom, Economics, Mathematical Statistics